<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: NodeJS | creativepsyco's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.mohitkanwal.com/blog/categories/nodejs/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.mohitkanwal.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-23T15:06:27+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.mohitkanwal.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mohit Kanwal]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[mohit.kanwal+blog@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Technologies Galore]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.mohitkanwal.com/blog/2012/11/02/new-technologies-galore/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-02T01:12:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.mohitkanwal.com/blog/2012/11/02/new-technologies-galore</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Most of the stuff is still under production, more details later</em></p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t know why but these days I am hooked to Javascript. Perhaps that&rsquo;s coz I write way too much Javascript these days or maybe the world is really moving to the client side of things. Now I don&rsquo;t want to go into the details of the holy war of server side vs client side of things. However, I do find that client side stuff is very exciting not to mention that completely open.</p>

<p>For client side development I am using a host of technologies to work my way around. These are BackboneJS, ExpressJS, NodeJS and Redis.</p>

<h2>Food For Thought</h2>

<p>Now you would be wondering how come so many *JS appended libraries. Man! if I had known myself I would tell but really don&rsquo;t know what is up with the JS convention anyways.</p>

<h2>NodeJS</h2>

<p>To me nodejs seems pretty darn powerful when it comes to serving requests. With it&rsquo;s event driven framework to go around I am sure it&rsquo;s the language of the server in the times to come. Although I would like to step back and think that Javascript is not really a <code>language</code> but more like a <code>scripting language</code> but I guess the perceptions will change over time. To start a simple node js server all you need is to install <a href="http://nodejs.org/">Node</a> first. My favorite for doing this is <a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/">Homebrew</a></p>

<p><code>bash
$ brew install node
</code></p>

<p>Here is a sample <code>server.js</code> file which acts as a Node web server.</p>

<p><code>js server.js
var http = require('http');
http.createServer(function (req, res) {
  res.writeHead(200, {'Content-Type': 'text/plain'});
  res.end('Hello World\n');
}).listen(1337, '127.0.0.1');
console.log('Server running at http://127.0.0.1:1337/');
</code>
To run this all you need to do is:</p>

<p><code>bash
$ node server.js
</code></p>

<p>And voila goto <code>localhost:1337</code> and be greeted by a HTML page response. Cool isn&rsquo;t it?</p>

<h2>ExpressJS</h2>

<p>Now we dive into a framework for creating web applications with Node. Why? Coz Frameworks rock and there is a clear well defined design strategy at work which frankly most of us would take a lot of time to devise. So why don&rsquo;t we use the community&rsquo;s advice and just do it!</p>

<p><a href="http://expressjs.com/">ExpressJS</a> makes the creation of web apps with Node such a breeze.</p>

<p>First you would need to install express. For this we would make use of the Node Package manager (NPM)</p>

<p><code>bash
$ npm install -g express
</code></p>

<p>This would put a bunch of stuff in the directory of our node app. ExpressJS comes with a cool generator (aka rails style) and one can make use of it to create the next scaffold.</p>

<p><code>bash
$ express --sessions --css stylus --ejs myapp
</code></p>

<p>So go ahead and start modifying code. Yay! Follow the guide at the <a href="http://expressjs.com/guide.html">ExpressJS Docs</a></p>

<h2>BackboneJS</h2>

<p>Server side Javascript is fine but what about client side javascript. For this we have <a href="http://backbonejs.org/">BackboneJS</a>, a client-side MVP (most people call it MVC or MV*) framework which organizes your code into awesome folders called <code>models</code>, <code>views</code> and <code>templates</code>. Find out more about it at the official website.</p>

<h2>Redis</h2>

<p>And lastly for persistence, I am looking at <a href="http://try.redis-db.com/">Redis</a>. I am still looking at it. So i will update this once I have more information about it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Node JS Script to run a web server for Backbone etc]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.mohitkanwal.com/blog/2012/10/22/node-js-script-to-run-a-web-server-for-backbone-etc/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T00:18:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.mohitkanwal.com/blog/2012/10/22/node-js-script-to-run-a-web-server-for-backbone-etc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The Problem</h2>

<p>Sometimes we find ourselves wanting to be able to host a webserver to test out some HTML or javascript functionality. For example when Cross Origin Resource Policy (CORS) does not allow running of scripts from outside the domain of the webserver.</p>

<h2>The Solution</h2>

<p>The solution is a simple piece of node js script living in the directory. Surprisingly it is way way small</p>

<p>``` javascript Sample NodeJS Script to run server
var connect = require(&lsquo;connect&rsquo;);
connect.createServer(</p>

<pre><code>connect.static(__dirname)
</code></pre>

<p>).listen(8080);
```</p>

<p>This would start listening for a request on port 8080 and then serve the files from the current directory.</p>

<p>In order to use you must put the code in a file called <em>server.js</em></p>

<p>And Also must install <code>connect</code> module via
<div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>  npm install connect
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>&mdash;mohit</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
