<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: philosophy | creativepsyco's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://creativepsyco.github.io/blog/categories/philosophy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://creativepsyco.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-23T18:16:58+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://creativepsyco.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mohit Kanwal]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A home called India]]></title>
    <link href="http://creativepsyco.github.io/blog/2012/12/11/a-home-called-india/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T22:36:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://creativepsyco.github.io/blog/2012/12/11/a-home-called-india</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>And now some random philosphical thoughts on what I think of India: my home</em></p>

<p><em>I am an Indian from India. For most of us, the buck stop right there. I grew up just like the rest of the kids in my colony: I thought we as a Nation are huge, the best in the world. Buoyed by my sense of patriotism I even wrote a story about an army related incursion in Kashmir which got published in Champak.I knew I had a passion for writing. Nationalism aside, 10 years out in the world, I don't think I am the same sane person I used to be back then.</em></p>

<h3>A lot has changed</h3>

<p>Industries grew. Computers overtook our lives. Terrorists became the No#1 menace of any democratic country/nation in the world. All this affected me mentally as a child. And that's because news was delivered to me in real-time by my Dad, who works in The Times of India (a leading English newspaper in India).</p>

<h3>Education was important, but not cheap and hence the expected returns</h3>

<p>Let's not digress into the discussion of arguing whether education was cheap or not or whether it must be equated to the same pedestal as the stock market which keeps toying between various shades of VIBGYOR. Let's just agree to the claim that Education was considered to be the golden ticket for the end of the road journey for which some people save, some people just hope to get along somehow. But this was not the case with Education. After chasing to be the brightest and the so-called <strong>cream</strong> I realized it too late that Education was merely a hall ticket to appear in examinations like the IIT and PMT, it was here that the real trading of horses was done, albeit in a grade-question-answer sort of fashion.</p>

<p>I don't know whether my battery ran out of juice or out of luck or out of hard work to run for these exams. I knew they were tough but I did not expect myself to face such obstacles, especially not after I donned the throne of being the <strong>cream</strong> in some colony, in some school.</p>

<p>A fat pay package comes because of education, and that's what everyone should think about. This is what I was told.</p>

<h3>Fundamentally flawed assumption</h3>

<p>If something is observed to be holding in a certain frame of reference does not mean it is true. I learnt this in statistics, unfortunately too late.</p>

<h3>Back to the point, India</h3>

<p>I see two systems here, an educational system and a money obsessed employment system. I don't know which one feeds the other. I can think of (Based on my Assumption above) the educational system being the culprit. A fine secondary education on my CV though does not allow me to make such a claim. On a closer detail however, it is revealed that major companies setup training institutes to train young graduates which sort of qualifies as an educational establishment, but I would like to argue otherwise as it is a directed process as compared to the seemingly freedom like approach of the Secondary school education system.</p>

<h3>India is full of opportunities and I can see it</h3>

<p>Talk about the BPO boom in India, its the past. Software is the new Hip trend these days. Degree does not matter, the company, the pay does. And everything else is a big fat circle called zero.</p>

<h3>Literally</h3>

<p>This is not the end, its just the beginning of a new discovery about a country I never found attractive.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
